Mykolas Viningas

Profile

I am a full-stack software engineer with multiple years of experience designing, building, and solving in the Ruby, JavaScript, and Go ecosystems. Most recently, I co-created Symphony ☑, an open-source framework that provides real-time collaboration functionality and ready-to-scale infrastructure to web applications.

Professional Experience

Creator, Software Engineer, Symphony (symphony-framework.github.io)

2023 - present

- Designed and created Symphony, an open-source real-time collaboration framework
- Prototyped and built a WebSocket server using Node.js and AWS services including S3, RDS for PostgreSQL, ElastiCache for Redis and DynamoDB
- Deployed iterations of the prototype infrastructure on AWS (EC2, ECS, Fargate)
- Built an NPM package for a client library that connects to the WebSocket server
- Wrote a RESTful API for accessing server metadata
- Created a dashboard interface to display static and live metric data using Remix, React, and Tailwind. Live metrics delivered using Server-Sent Events (SSEs)
- Developed a custom load-testing solution for the WebSocket server
- Engineered a Redis pub/sub solution to horizontally scale WebSocket servers and increase system capacity by more than 40x
- Automated the infrastructure deployment using AWS Cloud Development Kit via a custom CLI tool
- Prioritized scalability, fault tolerance, and separation of concerns when engineering solutions
- Authored Symphony's case study: symphony-framework.github.io
- Collaborated as part of a remote team of 4 engineers across 2 timezones using agile workflow

Software Engineer, *Self-employed*

2019 - 2022

Some of the projects and technologies used during this time:

- Terminal a real-time application for receiving and debugging webhooks (Next.js/React, TypeScript, ChakraUI, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, WebSockets)
- Todos a database-backed todo tracker application (Ruby, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, ¡Query, HTML, CSS)
- Contacts a single page contact manager application with Model-View-Controller structure on the front-end (Node.js, Express, JavaScript, Handlebars, HTML, CSS)

Skills

Back end

Node.js, Express, Ruby, Sinatra, Go, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful

APIs

Tooling

HTML, CSS

Front end

AWS, Digital Ocean,

JavaScript, TypeScript, ¡Query, React/Redux, Next.js,

Git/GitHub, Docker, Linux, Bash

Cloud

Heroku

Education

Launch School 17

2019 - 2022

A mastery-based study of Software Engineering fundamentals

Royal Academy of Music, University of London, Bachelor's degree, Jazz/Jazz studies

2013 - 2017